Mario Bourzac

Oakland, CA 94607

Mobile: 616-821-7563 | Website: http://mariobourzac.com | E-mail: mario.bourzac@gmail.com

SUMMARY

More than 10 years of experience as a freelance and staff writer for travel and destination journals, art & entertainment industry trades, B2C, and public grant writing. Skills include easy and open communications with interviewees, meticulous fact-checking, and deadline-driven time management.

SKILLS

- Writing: Technical, Content, Feature Article, Promotional, Entertainment
- Social Media: Twitter, Facebook, Bandcamp, HootSuite, Instagram
- Software: Zendesk, Shipstation, Shopify, WordPress, MailChimp, HTML/CSS, Photoshop, SEOmoz

EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, C&H Sugar (Contractor)

June 2018 - Present

Crockett, CA

C&H Sugar is part of ASR Group, the world's largest refiner of cane sugar. As a Technical Writer, my duties include:

- Constructing Training manuals to standardize processes on various production and packaging lines
- Collecting information through in-person interviews with Operators, Specialists, and Mechanics
- Curating information into step-by-step instructions for safe and effective machine operation
- Photograph individual steps for visual aids
- Edit photographs for size, lighting, and resolution

Copywriter, Claremont Rug Company

January 2017 - June 2018

Oakland, CA

Claremont Rug Company specializes in offering rarely found antique Persian carpets and rugs that possess great artistic individuality and uncompromising craftsmanship. They are the only Oriental rug company ever listed on Robb Report's "Best of the Best." CRC caters to connoisseurs and offers in home visits around the country to interested clients. Responsibilities include:

- Research and write company's Rug Education Guide
- Edit and rewrite product descriptions on company website
- Oversee data management systems
- Edit photos for e-mail marketing and B2C mailings

Freelance Writer and Editor, www.mariobourzac.com

2006 - Present

Grand Rapids, MI; South Bend, IN; Bay Area, CA

Regularly contribute articles, create content, and update CMS for several publications and websites. Past clients include:

- West Michigan Environmental Action Council
- Kalamazoo Shopper
- Kalamazoo Gazette
- Shore Magazine

Promotions Manager and Musician

2006 - Present

Oakland, CA; Global

Lead marketing and outreach efforts for various independent bands as a musician, songwriter, and promoter. Managed all aspects of event promotion, including onsite advertising, merchandising and venue negotiations.

Customer Service and Media Content, Social Imprints

September 2014 – May 2015

San Francisco, CA

Social Imprints is a merchandise and apparel printing company specializing in promotional merchandise. Additionally, they offer clients the option to host and operate their respective web stores. The web store service also includes stocking client merchandise and customer service management. As part of my role:

- Shipped and tracked packages for 20+ web stores; correlated shipping error information
- Customer Service; Zendesk certified; maintained connection with customers when errors occurred
- Updated & organized Zendesk platform to categorize & track errors

.

Data Team Member, Instacart

July 2013 – September 2014

San Francisco, CA

Instacart is an online shopping service that provides same-day grocery delivery to homes and businesses. Based in San Francisco, the startup company recently expanded into Chicago, IL. Austin, TX, and Boston, MA. Mv duties included:

- Sort through and correct meta data for website to ensure accurate product information
- Ensure information is accurate and spelled correctly
- Photograph items with Ortery Light Box for 360 images on website

Independent Contractor, TaskRabbit

March 2013 - March 2014

San Francisco, CA

TaskRabbit is an Internet based service that allows businesses and individuals to outsource errands and skilled tasks to capable and efficient workers. Members from their talent pool complete tasks in a timely and professional manner, allowing their customers to focus their attention on other priorities. Through TaskRabbit I became a first call for Instacart, an online shopping service, to collect data for their website, as well as match the information in their system. In this function:

- Successfully navigated the city to transport customers and items for delivery and presentations
- Communicated effectively with store managers and employees while collecting data for Instacart
- Negotiated price and time limits for individual tasks

Writing Intern, Pachamama Alliance

March 2013 - June 2013

San Francisco, CA

The Pachamama Alliance is an organization working to empower indigenous people of the Amazon to preserve their lands and culture. To do so, they employ a number of fund raising, outreach and cultural immersion programs designed to interest and inspire participants. As a writing intern, I was responsible for:

- Developing content for blog posts and Facebook entries
- Researching topics to develop articles consistent with mission statement
- Posting, scheduling, and editing posts in Facebook and WordPress with HTML
- Creating SEO pages to draw readers using Google Adwords and SEOmoz (now Moz)

Staff Writer, Michiana Entertainer & NWI Entertainer South Bend, IN

February 2008 – March 2011

The Michiana Entertainer is an entertainment magazine based out of South Bend, IN. The publication focuses on nightlife, entertainment, and community events. Coverage and distribution areas include southwest Michigan and northeast Indiana areas. As a staff writer, my duties included:

- Responsible for creating feature articles every month
- Interviewed both Tommy Chong and Sevendust for M.E.
- Created articles for every section of the magazine
- Helped generate interest in local establishments and events by developing buzz through highlighting upcoming special events

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Western Michigan University, 2005

- Major: Sociology, emphasis in Social Psychology
- Major: English, emphasis in Practical Writing